Guide to the Randolph Linsly Simpson African-American Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Series I. Visual Material
  - 20TH CENTURY PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Unknown photographer Two cars parked side by side. Man in shorts leans against grill of one on left. Early 20th century photograph, 3-7/16 x 5-1/16, circa 1950 (Box 22)
      Item #908
    - Unknown photographer Police officer directs tow truck towards car on curb. Early 20th century photograph, 3-1/2 x 5-1/8, circa 1950 (Box 22)
      Item #909
    - Unknown photographer Child stands in wash between two rows of wooden shacks. Early 20th century photograph, 3-1/2 x 5-3/4, 1915 (Box 22)
      One of group of five of turpentine camp.
      Item #910
    - Unknown photographer Model T Ford amidst palm trees. Early 20th century photograph, 3-1/2 x 5-3/4, 1915 (Box 22, Folder 947)
      Item #911
    - Unknown photographer Group of women and children standing in a circle playing pretend game. Early 20th century photograph, 3-1/2 x 5-3/4, 1915 (Box 22)
      Item #912
    - Unknown photographer Group of three women and 13 children grouped in front of rough wooden building. Early 20th century photograph, 3-1/2 x 5-3/4, 1915 (Box 22)
      In pencil, verso, "Teacher & children at Tomoka Mission Turpentine camp. Deland Road." One of five of turpentine camp.
      Item #913
    - Unknown photographer Three women, eight children. Early 20th century photograph, 3-1/2 x 5-3/4, 1915 (Box 22)
      One of a group of five of turpentine camp.
      Item #914
    - Unknown photographer Lady Standing on walk in front of porch steps of large building; second woman entering door deep background. Early 20th century photograph, 5-5/16 x 3-1/4., 1915 (Box 22)
      One of a group of five.
      Item #915
    - Unknown photographer Same lady depicted in 915 and one other standing at back of group of five girls. Early 20th century photograph, 5-1/4 x 3-1/4, 1915 (Box 22)
      Item #916
    - Unknown photographer Girl's basketball team, wearing sailor-style shirt and neckscarves, lying on grass; grove of trees and large house in background. Early 20th century photograph, 3-3/8 x 5-9/16, 1915 (Box 22)
      One of a group of five. One girl holds basketball, "[?] 1915" in chalk.
      Item #917
    - Unknown photographer Lady standing behind table with food in room ready for festive occasion. American flags, flowers, "Tenth Anniversary" in chalk on blackboard. Early 20th century photograph, 3-9/16 x 5-9/16, 1915 (Box 22)
      Item #918
    - Unknown photographer Girls basketball team depicted standing, grove of trees in background, large house to left; same subjects and location as 917. Early 20th century photograph. 3-1/4 x 5-1/4., 1915 (Box 22)
      Item #919
    - Unknown photographer Young man in suit seated in domestic interior. Early 20th century photograph, 3-3/8 x 2-3/8, circa 1930 (Box 22)
      See 874, same interior, but additional cup on shelf.
      Item #920
    - Unknown photographer Three men in car; black man standing, foreground. Early 20th century photograph, 2-1/8 x 5, circa 1920 (Box 22)
      Item #921
    - Unknown photographer Soldier in World War II Uniform, standing beside jeep. Early 20th century photograph, 4-9/16 x 3-1/4, circa 1942 (Box 22)
      Item #922
    - Unknown photographer Soldier in World War II Uniform standing in front of bridge, Packard and other cars behind. Early 20th century photograph, 4-1/2 x 2-3/4, 1942 (Box 22)
      In pencil, verso, "July, 1942. Albany."
      Item #923
    - Unknown photographer Soldier in World War II Uniform standing in front of bridge, Packard and other cars behind. Early 20th century photograph, 4-1/2 x 2-3/4, 1942 (Box 22)
      Identical to 923; slightly different view.
      Item #924
    - Unknown photographer Portrait of "Melvin"; Soldier in sun helmet, gas mask slung on right shoulder. Early 20th century photograph, 4 x 3, circa 1942 (Box 22, Folder 948)
      In ink, verso, " To My Darling Young Sister Gertrude From Her Big Soldier Brother, Melvin."
      Item #925
    - Unknown photographer Family group: man, woman, child on porch with dog. Early 20th century photograph, 3-1/4 x 4-3/8, circa 1939 (Box 22)
      Item #926
    - Unknown photographer Boy watches black farmers operate mule drawn binder in field. Early 20th century photograph 5 x 3-7/16, circa 1920 (Box 22)
      In pencil, verso, "Harvesting rice in Louisiana with Binder near .... [writing runs off edge"
      Item #927
    - Unknown photographer Two boys playing in pile of snow beside "[?]eck's Garage." Early 20th century photograph. 5-1/4 x 3, circa 1932 (Box 22)
      Item #928
    - Unknown photographer Couple: man in chauffeur's uniform; lady in white dress stand in open embrace beside large automobile. Early 20th century photograph 4-1/2 x 3-1/4, circa 1950 (Box 22)
      Item #929
    - Unknown photographer Black lady with two black children and one white child, depicted before free standing stone fireplace in back yard. Early 20th century photograph, 5-1/4 x 3-1/8, circa 1945 (Box 22)
      Item #930
    - Unknown photographer Young couple seated on steps with iron railings, "223" on door. Early 20th century photograph, 4-3/4 x 3, circa 1946 (Box 22)
      Signage by door, "Upper flat to let."
      Item #931
    - Unknown photographer Park setting: elderly couple stand before large tree; people walking, sitting on grass, cars in background. Early 20th century photograph 5 x 3-1/2, circa 1955 (Box 22)
      Item #932
    - Unknown photographer Full length portrait of man seated, wearing felt hat, two-tone shoes. Early 20th century photograph, 3-1/2 x 2-1/4, circa 1925 (Box 22)
      Item #933
    - Unknown photographer Full length portrait of man seated, wearing hat, rustic snow scene set. Early 20th century photograph, 3-1/2 x 2-1/2, circa 1950 (Box 22)
      Item #934
    - Unknown photographer View of oil field workers on rig. Early 20th century photograph, 3-1/2 x 2-1/2, circa 1940 (Box 22)
      Item #935
    - Unknown photographer Double circular snapshot with floral background, bust length portraits of lady in two different poses. Early 20th century photograph, 1-3/4 x 3-5/16, circa 1915 (Box 22)
      Item #936
    - Unknown photographer Instant photo, head of man with light colored hat. Early 20th century photograph. 2 x 1-1/2, circa 1940 (Box 22)
      Item #937
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York Men in lines before machines at US Mint packing bags; stacked bags in background. Early 20th century photograph, 3-5/16 x 3-5/16., circa 1939 (Box 22)
      In pencil, verso, "Counting and packaging US coins at Mint."
      Item #938
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York Man in apron stands at rolling mill, US Mint. Early 20th century photograph, 3-5/16 x 3-1/4, circa 1939 (Box 22)
      In pencil, verso, "Rolling Mill -- US Mint."
      Item #939
    - Creedman, Cambridge (MA) School Group: students with teachers at center lined up beside brick building; banner "Roberts School," in negative, "Class of 1923." Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 9-7/8 x 11-7/8
      Item #940
    - Unknown photographer View of large clapboard church with minister standing on steps. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 9-1/2 x 11-7/8, undated
      Sign on building: "Shiloh Baptist Church. Rev. W.J. Smith, Pastor."
      Item #941
    - McKay, Akron, OH Family group standing in front of house; boy with bicycle. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 9-1/2 x 12, undated
      Item #942
    - Millers, Sabina, Ohio School group with teacher on concrete steps before brick building. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 10 X 12, circa 1905
      Item #943
    - Crown Studio, Bridgeport, CT School group; Junior High Graduating Class. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 10 X 13-7/8, 1922
      Photographer identified in negative as is date.
      Item #944
    - Unknown photographer Workers in tunnel with picks and shovels. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 10 X 12, circa 1920
      Item #945
    - Unknown photographer "Use Heckers' Buckwheat. Hecker, Jones, Jewell Milling Co." Display booth with chefs and servers at counter. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 10 X 12, undated
      Item #946
    - Ralph Harris & Co., Boston Three children in two-wheeled donkey cart. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 10 X 12, circa 1910
      Item #947
    - Hobby Studio, New York Group portrait of a baseball team; uniforms marked "Glenmore." Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 10 X 12, circa 1914
      Item #948
    - Jim Predmore, Everett, NM Group portrait of postmen stand before post office. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 11 X 14, 1909
      Date with photographer identified verso.
      Item #949
    - Unknown photographer Group of six snapshots mounted together labeled: "The Darkest Side of College Life." Young men and women in aprons and waiter uniforms; one tray with glasses. Early 20th century photograph, board mount, 9 x 12-3/4, circa 1920
      Label attached verso identifies set as being for publication in the "Sea Gull."
      Item #950
    - Crosby, New Haven Group portrait of football team with coaches. Early 20th century photograph, matted, 11 1-2 X 13-1/2, 1936
      Coaches and players identified by title and position, along with opponents and record, in badly fading ink verso.
      Item #951
    - Unknown photographer Group of men in formal attire stand at steps before building, one woman top center; waiter/butler in white jacket at right. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 10 X 12, circa 1925
      Item #952
    - Unknown photographer "Harvesting Rice, Louisiana, U.S." Reapers and binders pulled by teams of mules, and laborers, harvest crop. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 9-1/2 X 12, circa 1920
      Recto, lower right, "The Philadelphia Museums." Long descriptive text verso.
      Apparently of a series with 954-956.
      Item #953
    - Unknown photographer "Baling Cotton, Arkansas." First floor of a cotton gin where raw cotton is being pressed and tied into bales. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 9 ½ X 12, circa 1920
      "The Philadelphia Museums," recto, lower right. Long descriptive text verso.
      Item #954
    - Unknown photographer "Picking Cotton, Arkansas." Workers picking cotton in field; mule team hitched to wagon nearby; overseer with two small children. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 9-3/4 X 12, circa 1920
      Item #955
    - Unknown photographer "Harvesting Flax, Washington." Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 9-1/2 X 12, circa 1920
      Item #956
    - Unknown photographer "Cotton Gins, Arkansas." Three double- breasted cotton gins in operation on third floor of cotton gin. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 9-3/4 x 11-3/4, circa 1920
      Long descriptive text verso.
      Item #957
    - Unknown photographer "Baling Cotton, Arkansas." Duplicates 954. Early 20th century photograph, mounted, 9-3/4 X 11-3/4, circa 1920
      No "Philadelphia Museums" stamp recto. Long descriptive text verso.
      Item #958
    - Unknown photographer "Cotton Market, Birmingham, Alabama." Public square in Birmingham filled with farmers, wagons hitched to mule teams filled with bales of cotton. Early 20th century photograph, 9-3/4 X 11-3/4, circa 1920
      Item #959
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY "Stevens Courts-first negro family moving in:" man stands at rear of pickup backed to curb; children on walk; woman stands at door to apartment in complex. 20th century photograph, 7-7/8 x 10., circa 1945 (Box 22, Folder 949)
      In ink, verso, "Texarkana, Texas" Typewritten, "Stevens Courts -- first Negro family moving in."
      Item #960
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY "Shack transformed into modern cottage in six hours:" partly demolished shack; worker on roof; other men in overalls nearby. 20th century photograph, 8-1/8 x 9-15/16, 1934 (Box 22)
      Typewritten, attached, "Shack Transformed into Modern Cottage in Six Hours -- Chicago, Ill. October 24, 1934. World's Fair visitors yesterday saw...."
      Item #961
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY "Modern Edition Book Manufacturing; Printing Division; Ink wareroom and laundry for wiping cloths. (Kingsport Press, Kingsport, Tenn.)" Men at work in factory. 20th century photograph, 7 x 9 (Box 22)
      Identification typewritten and attached verso.
      Item #962
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY Two men in tunnel tighten nuts with large wrench on shoulders. 20th century photograph, 8-7/8 x 7, circa 1927 (Box 22)
      In pencil, verso, "Cocking nuts in street arches of vehicular tunnel between New York and New Jersey."
      Item #963
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY Trucks filled with crates of chickens, horsedrawn wagon stand before large building, "West Washington Market." Workers enter side door. 20th century photograph, 7-7/8 x 9-1/2, circa 1925 (Box 22)
      Typewritten attached, "Series Live stock. Thanksgiving Turkeys Arrive At West Washington Market." Descriptive text. "3899B4 -- A general view of the West Washington Market."
      Item #964
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY Men in smocks, butcher's aprons, heavy jackets, one holding live turkey, stand beside horsedrawn wagon full of crates. Sign in background, "Krakaur Poultry Co." 20th century photograph. 8 x 10, circa 1925 (Box 22)
      Typewritten attached, "Series Live stock: Thanksgiving Turkeys Arrive at West Washington Market." Descriptive text. "2900B4 -- Checking shipments at the West Washington Market."
      Item #965
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY Men and women in field harvesting cranberries. 20th century photograph, 8-1/2 x 6-5/8, 1922 October 23 (Box 22)
      Typewritten attached, "Getting Ready For Thanksgiving..and for Christmas.. Showing cranberry pickers on the job at Wareham, Mass. 10/23/22."
      Item #966
    - Walt Hays, St. Louis, MO Construction workers at work. 20th century photograph, 8-1/8 x 10, 1957 (Box 22)
      In pencil, verso, "Construction Work in St. Louis, MO."
      Item #967
    - J. Carver Harris, Pix Publishing, Inc., New York, [NY] Four boys sit on the dock behind a row of buckets and a pile of shrimp. 20th century photograph, 8 x 9-7/8, 1923 (Box 22)
      Typewritten attached, "HARR/23 Shrimp Fishing is a Big Industry" followed by descriptive text and photographer identification.
      Item #968
    - Unknown photographer Movie still: Louis Armstrong standing at foot of steps with iron railing, wearing white uniform and cork helmet, holding trumpet to his lips. 20th century photograph, 10 x 8, circa 1930 (Box 22)
      Typewritten attached recto, "F.9018 Louis Armstrong Playing the Trumpet in a 1930's Movie."
      Item #969
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY "2442 America's Youngest 'Stars' Arrive" Nicholas Brothers and Maud Russell on arrival at Waterloo Station to appear in London production of "Blackbirds." 20th century photograph, 10 x 8, 1936 April 6 (Box 22, Folder 950)
      Typewritten descriptive text attached verso.
      Item #970
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY Double portrait: Norval Baptie and Ted Lewis; Lewis at left; Norval, right in joker costume playing saxophone; both wear speed skates. 20th century photograph, 9-5/16 x 7-1/8, circa 1940 (Box 22)
      Item #971
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY "S/321A907 80-Ton Whale:" man stands on the back of an enormous Blue Fin whale. 20th century photograph, 8 x 10-1/8, circa 1927 (Box 22)
      Item #972
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY "#313,649 Jazz Ban Aids Christmas Charity Fund"; Ted Lewis Famous Jazz Band performs in street. 20th century photograph, 8-1/4 x 6-1/2, circa 1940 (Box 22)
      Item #973
    - R.E. Hawkins, Lakewood, OH Scene in a Foundry with men at work. 20th century photograph, 9-1/2 x 7-1/2, circa 1925 (Box 22)
      Of a series with 975 and 976.
      Item #974
    - R.E. Hawkins, Lakewood, OH Scene in a Foundry, men at work. 20th century photograph, 7-5/8 x 9-1/2, circa 1925 (Box 22)
      In series with previous and next.
      Item #975
    - R.E. Hawkins, Lakewood, OH Scene in a Foundry, men at work. 20th century photograph, 9-1/2 x 7-5/8, circa 1925 (Box 22)
      In series with previous two.
      Item #976
    - Unknown photographer Lionel Hampton and his Band; shot at a raking angle in x-y plane. 20th century photograph, 8 x 10, circa 1930 (Box 22)
      In pencil, verso, "Lionel Hampton c. 1930's."
      Item #977
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY Sing Sing Prison: very large room with men seated in rows eating. 20th century photograph, 10-1/4 x 8, 1906 (Box 22)
      In pencil, verso, "Prisons - Ossining NY. No. 97696. Sing Sing Prison 1906"
      Item #978
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY Sing Sing Prison: men walking in prison yard. 20th century photograph, 8 x 10-3/16, circa 1930 (Box 22)
      In pencil, verso, "Prisons - Ossining NY. No. 116 R 191. General view of the yards. Showing prisoners at Sing Sing Prison. c. 1930's"
      Item #979
    - Oliver of Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY Dilapidated shacks with three children out front. 20th century photograph, mounted,7-5/8 x 10-1/4, circa 1930 (Box 22, Folder 951)
      Recto on mount, "Classification: Birmingham, Ala. Negative No. O.3881 Title: Ave. C. and Alley C, 13th & 14th Strs. So. Court surrounded by 21 Hovels. Most have porch, [cont. verso] toilets & inside water, houses in poor condition. Rent $7.00 per mo."
      Item #980
    - Unknown photographer Chain gang in stripes working on road, guard with Winchester carbine watching. 20th century photograph, 6 x 8-1/2, circa 1930 (Box 22)
      Item #981
    - Underwood-Stratton, New York, NY "13754-Alabama. Negro children." 20th century photograph, 7-3/4 x 9-3/4, circa 1940 (Box 22)
      Item #982
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY Mr. Roscoe Kent and wife: old couple shown at kitchen table in US Dept of Agriculture publicity for food stamps. 20th century photograph, 8 x 10, circa 1950 (Box 22)
      Descriptive text typewritten verso.
      Item #983
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY Two students with library book truck, sign reads "Our Library on Wheels P.S. 44," stand at head of 5th and 6th grade classroom. 20th century photograph, 8 x 10-1/8, 1936 (Box 22)
      Typewritten description with date attached.
      Item #984
    - WPA Photographic Section "14960, Columbia, South Carolina. WPA workmen digging malaria drainage ditch." 20th century photograph, 8-1/2 x 6-1/2, circa 1930 (Box 22)
      Description and identification verso.
      Item #985
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY "Trench warfare against mosquitoes!- -Novel campaign directed over 650-mile Front in Greater New York." Two men pour oil over refuse strewn wetland in Elmhurst. 20th century photograph, 10-1/8 x 8, circa 1940 (Box 22)
      Descriptive text attached. See also 1018, 1020, 1026.
      Item #986
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY Movie still: Eddie Anderson as Noah in _Green Pastures._ 20th century photograph, 9-1/4 x 7-1/4, 1936 (Box 22)
      In pencil, verso, "'And the flood subsiding' Eddie Anderson as Noah with his doves in the version of The Green Pastures
      Item #987
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY Members from Our Gang: "Petie," Joe Cobb, Farina, and the Turk prepare to slaughter "Wheezer" the Thanksgiving turkey. 20th century photograph, 6-5/8 x 8-1/2, circa 1940 (Box 22)
      Typewritten description attached.
      Item #988
    - Wide World Photos Paul Robeson as Othello; Uta Hagen as Desdemona in Theater Guild production. 20th century photograph, 9 x 7, 1943 (Box 22)
      Item #989
    - Marion Palfi (copyright) Half length portrait of Hazel Scott at the piano. 20th century photograph, 9-5/8 x 7-3/4, circa 1940 (Box 22, Folder 952)
      Item #990
    - Mills Artists, Inc. Full face publicity still of Cab Calloway, autographed. 20th century photograph, 10 x 8, circa 1940 (Box 22)
      Item #991
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY Newsboy with papers in the middle of Los Angeles traffic. 20th century photograph, 8-1/8 x 10. (Box 22)
      Item #992
    - Unknown photographer View of Interior of Hospital Ward; white doctor and nurses; elderly black female patients. 20th century photograph, 6-1/2 x 8-1/2, circa 1910 (Box 22)
      Item #993
    - Unknown photographer View of interior of hospital ward; white doctor and nurses; elderly black male patients. 20th century photograph, 6-1/2 x 8-1/2, circa 1910 (Box 22)
      Item #994
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, NY View of Schubert piano factory in NY; workman at pumice polishing machine. 20th century photograph, 6-1/2 x 8-1/2, 1923 (Box 22)
      Item #995
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York Bust length portrait of man standing in clericals, Roman collar. 20th century photograph, 9 x 7-1/8, circa 1925 (Box 22)
      In pencil, verso, "Harlem priest"
      Item #996
    - Unknown photographer View of nightclub interior: couples at tables, many more dancing, to music by band, at right. Reflected in mirror on far wall, "Chuck Collins Black Bottom." 20th century photograph, 8 x 10, circa 1925 (Box 22)
      Item #997
    - Unknown photographer Two views of Rockingham Race Track printed together. Upper: racehorses in action: Horse #4 wins by a neck. Lower: Horse #4 with jockey up, black groom and young white boy. 20th century photograph, 10 x 8, 1946 (Box 22)
      Item #998
    - Unknown photographer Three quarter length group portrait; three men of different generations, one holds revolver. 20th century photograph, 8 x 9-7/8, circa 1935 (Box 22)
      Item #999
    - Paul's Photo Studio, Brooklyn, NY Full length standing portrait, lady in light colored floor length dress stands in front of piano, vases with many flowers. 20th century photograph, 9-7/8 x 8, circa 1940 (Box 22, Folder 953)
      Item #1000
    - Vandamm, New York, NY Publicity still: scene from the New York Theater Guild's production of Porgy. 20th century photograph, 8 x 10, circa 1930 (Box 22)
      In pencil, verso, "Scene from the NY Theater Guild's "Porgy" Lyceum. 3 days Mon. Tue. Wed."
      Item #1001
    - Unknown photographer "Chauffeurs' Banquet, 1936:" in ink recto beneath photograph. Men and women prepare to dine at two long banquet tables. 20th century photograph, 6-1/4 x 9-9/16, 1937 (Box 22)
      Item #1002
    - Unknown photographer Snapshot view of elderly man setting up home movie projector as two others and a woman watch. 20th century photograph, 5 x 7., 1937 (Box 22)
      Item #1003
    - Campbell, New York, NY Full length portrait of Katherine Campbell in suggestive pose. 20th century photograph, 10 x 8, 1934 (Box 22)
      Item #1004
    - Campbell, New York, NY Standing publicity photograph of girl in bathing suit and cap. 20th century photograph, 10 x 8, circa 1930 (Box 22)
      Item #1005
    - MCA Management photo "Helen Humes, Featured with Count Basie and His Orchestra." 20th century photograph, 10 x 8, circa 1940 (Box 22)
      Item #1006
    - Unknown photographer Enlarged snapshot of Alice and Lizzie: two young women, one seated, the other stands, amidst lush foliage. 20th century photograph, 9 x 7, 1939 (Box 22)
      In ink, verso, "Hold Tight. Alice & Lizzie, Sunset Ridge, Hobe Sound. Fla 1939"
      Item #1007
    - Hirsch? Floyd Patterson gets physical examination by three doctors at N.Y. State Boxing Commission Office; Joe Louis looks on. 20th century photograph, 8 x 10, 1960 June 6 (Box 22)
      Descriptive text in which figures are identified verso.
      Item #1008
    - Unknown photographer Half length portrait of unknown sports figure, holding cigarette. 20th century photograph, 10 x 8, 1944 February 21 (Box 22)
      Date stamp and job number verso.
      Item #1009